ladies and gentlemen good day and
welcome to the Russia Decor limited Q3
FY 23 conference call hosted by Asian
market Securities Limited this
conference may contain forward-looking
statements about the company which are
based on the beliefs opinions and
expectations of the company has a date
of this call
these statements are not guarantees of
the future performance and involved
risks and uncertainties that are
difficult to predict
actual results May differ from
expectations projections Etc whether
expressed or implied
participants are requested to exercise
caution while referring to such
statements and remarks
as a reminder all possible lines will be
in the lesson only mode and there will
be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes
security assistance during the
conference call please signal an
operator by pressing star and then zero
on your Touchstone phone
please note that this conference is
being recorded
I now hand the conference over to Mr
Karen Batalia from Asian market
Securities limited thank you and over to
you
security
from the management side we have with us
Mr executive director
CEO and Kirin cardia CFO
over to you
uh good morning ladies and gentlemen and
welcome to the Russian record limited
earning conference call for the third
quarter in nine months ended on 31st
December 22.
I would like to thank Asian market
Securities for arranging this call and
all the participants for taking the time
to join the call
advisors
we have shared the shared and uploaded
the investors presentation on the
exchange and Hope you all have gone
through the same
let me share with you
some of the key highlights of the third
quarter in nine months during which we
have recorded the growth of 26 percent
and 46 percent respectively in our
operating revenues
both our laminate and MDF business has
shown steady progress in this period
our laminate businesses registered a
growth of 18 during this quarter
laminates grew by 41 percent in export
compared to last year's highlights
highlighting the strong demand of the
product manufactured by our company in
the global markets
in the domestic market with the
significant steps taken we are able to
improve the price realization which
helped us to achieve a bigger margin
over 10 percent in the laminate business
we have displayed positive performance
in our MDF business during the quarter
and have registered the growth of 27
percent by the value and 22 percent by
the volume
realization in the domestic industry for
the plain ndf was subdued as there was
an continued pressure from the higher
Imports
however we are confident that with the
targets of increased contribution of
value added products we are in position
to mitigate this trend and deliver the
significant growth in the coming quarter
during the quarter we had we have made
substantial progress in our geographical
Presence by adding 80 new dealers and
Distributors both in laminate and MDF
segment we should further enable us in
catering a larger customer base and
increase the visibility of the Brand's
rushil and veer
we are continuously collaborating with
the local Carpenters across the country
conducting the workshop to educate them
on the benefits of MDF also enhancing
their skill issues of the ndf for
delivering the effective
to the End customer
we are confident that with this branding
distribution and channel partner connect
initiative we should be able to achieve
strong growth in with stable ebitda
margins going ahead
during the quarter apart from the
supplied ratio from the Imports of plane
mbf there were also a marginal increase
in the wood price
the contribution of this factors
impacted the editor margins in the MDF
business compared to Quarter Two even
though their has been Improvement on a
year-on-year basis however to safeguard
ourselves from this headwinds we are
working on various fronts to ensure we
deliver the steady expansion in the
margins going forward
we are constantly engaging the various
stakeholders to identify and collect the
data in terms of requirement and
preferences of customer our in-house R D
team is continuously working to improve
the durability of our product and
develop more value-added products
we have also identified a few areas
where we can efficiently utilize and
optimize our resources to boost our
margins even further
we are timing our production schedule in
a systematic way into the optimum
capacity utilization in
in line with the industry demand
this will help us to stay ahead and
deliver our customers with a quality
product in the reasonable price
these initiatives should enable
volume expansion higher realization and
greater productivity in both laminate
and MDF segment
on the web reduction front I would like
to highlight that we have recently
announced the fundraise by the way of
right issues which should help us
significantly reduce the depths apart
from this our healthy cash generation
from the operations will further support
our Capital requirements and strengthen
the balance sheet
currently we have a capex plan of rupees
60 crore for our laminate business this
is this is to manufacture jumbo laminate
sheets which we have planned to export
to Europe USA Australia and other Global
markets
work on this initiative with using full
swing and it's expected to be
operational by quarter one financially
or 25.
that is all from my side I would like to
hand over a call to our CFO Mr hiran
fazia who shall take you through the
financial highlights thank you very much
good morning and thank you bye let me
take you through key financial
highlights for the quarter and
the nine months ended 31st December
2022. our Q3
mm has
ended
achieving our set targets
for the financial year and going forward
from there
so far as the quarter is concerned we
have reported operating revenues of
210.3 crore
a growth of about 26 percent compared to
166.8 crore
this was driven by the strong growth in
both MDS and language segments
MDA business revenues grew by 27 on
year-on-year basis contributing 152.8
crore in Q3 fy23
compared to
120.6 crore and Q3 f523
laminate contributor 56 crore in Q3 f523
compared to 47.3 crore in Q3 fy22
that is the growth of 18 percent
ebitda for the quarter after adjusting
for the forest laws stood at 38.1 crore
as against 19 crore in Q3 fy22
that is year over year growth of 101
percent
net profits to that 10.2 crores as
against 7.3 crore in Q3 at 522
again a growth of 40.5 percent on
year-on-year business
while ebitda margin increased by 670
pound business point in Q3 for 23. to
18.1 percent as against 11.4 percent
during the Q3 of previous Financial year
23.
during the card quarter on MDF current
our export volumes increase
significantly compared to the quarter
last year while our export volumes by
six percent on year on your basis
for the nine months and their 31st
December 2022 the net revenue from its
operations to that
624 crore a year-on-year growth of 45.5
percent here I would like to mention
that last year turnover that is 624
crore has already been achieved
in the three quarters of Current
financial year
while mbf contributed the 462.6 crore in
nine months
that is the growth of 59 laminate
contributed 156.5 crores in nine months
growth of 12.
editor for the nine months of financial
year stood at 133.7 crore as against
42.4 crore in the previous year
again a growth of 215 000 on
year-on-year basis
this is again adjusted for the Forex
loss in the nine month period net profit
was at 64.1 crore in nine months with a
margin of 10.3 percent
with the significant Improvement in
financial performance till nine months
of f523 we look forward to the financial
year delivering outstanding numbers this
should also provide a robust platform
for the next financial year
this is all from my side I would like to
now request operator to open the store
for questions and answers
we will now begin the question after
session participants who wish to ask a
question may press star and one on your
Touchstone telephone
if you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue you may press star and
two
for assuming the request to use handsets
while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we'll wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles
we have the first question on the line
of Karan patelia please go ahead
hi sir good morning thank you for the
opportunity so I just wanted to have
some clarity on on the CBD which we were
expecting somewhere in the second week
of January so what are the new timelines
now and what what percentage of CBD
could protect or received the domestic
players that would be helpful
uh thank you Karan for the question
first of all uh there is the Judgment
from the high court has already been
passed from Delhi High Court until now
we have not we have not got the concrete
judgment in our hands so we'll share the
details with you once we have the
Judgment in our hand thank you
foreign
thank you
participants who wish to ask a question
may press star and one on your desktop
on Telephone
participants who wish to ask a question
may press star and one on a touchstone
telephone
we are the next question from the line
of we need Shankar from JM Financial
please go ahead
hi sir thank you for the opportunity
uh so I just wanted to ask on the price
cut you have taken during the quarter uh
third quarter and any in during January
yeah good morning Mr Shankar I think
there is no price hike taken place in
our first quarter and even in the month
of January February or even in last
quarter also local
any price cut have you taken
price cut price cut
price reduction in last quarter we we
said that there was some effect of three
to five percent in uh
uh some areas not all areas
okay and so can you highlight uh which
area over there it was mainly uh South
and West
okay
I'm sure if you can also highlight uh
the breakup of plain and tree laminated
MDF mix
uh at present the ratio overall ratio of
mbf is almost 28 is our value and uh
balance is our plane grid which includes
exports too
okay thank you I have more questions I
will come back yeah please
thank you
we have the next question from the line
of
keshavati from hdsc Securities please go
ahead
I just wanted to understand or use
strategy because what we have seen you
know other branded players have not
taken more price
uh it's very difficult to say whether
price cut is there or not if I don't
change my price list it doesn't mean I
have not taken the price list price cut
there are there are ways to parcel the
credits
okay so got it so you are saying more or
less yes
industry always maybe you might play
with incentive or some other things so
you were in line the industry
understanding very simple if you want to
maintain your market share
you can command premium at some level
you cannot do all the things
thank you
I missed it I just wanted to understand
one more thing you know as we are you
know hearing that the imported MDF is
selling that 25 discount versus players
like you so the 25 is already a big
difference so what is the normal level
which it can sell because my
understanding is ten percent is
something let me tell you the ass on
that
the plot landed cost if I take about the
highest selling product pays around 50
15 to 18 percent
and if we go further uh down like uh
sorry for the central like Hyderabad
going through all the you know places
located far from sea areas then the
price difference is only 12 percent
okay
okay but the price difference has
increased for a very importantly so will
it be able to understand more price
strategies on your store right now in
Waterford
can you repeat again I'm sorry I'm not
able to
okay
I'm not able to hear properly hello is
it better now
yeah right yeah so I was saying as the
price difference with imported MDF is
increasing so will it be fair to assume
there would be more price cut in storing
water core or quarter one no I guess you
can see our volume and our
Top Line
so we really don't see because this this
import prices is stable since uh October
September October
because they have reached to probably
the bottom price
reduction in uh sorry in selling price
of imports and yes there is currency
fluctuations like sometime it is 81.83
so data is this exposure is something
that importers are considering
so we really don't see any price Cuts in
yeah
okay and what sort of volume and margin
you are looking for
we really want to make sure that we
maintain our uh you know market share
that's one of our priorities
so definitely it will help us to utilize
our capacity also
and yes we want to increase our
value-added business too because we can
see that from our AP plant in Quarter
Two our value-added business was nine
percent now in quarter feet has reached
to 13 percent
okay
good choice you will prioritize volume
over margin even if it comes at a
expense of a lower margin we will
prioritize volume
definitely it's not a question of
priority giving giving the priorities to
volume it's all about balancing entire
thing but yes market share is very
important we we have to consider new
capacity addition as well
so we can not simply you know
[Music]
we have to maintain our Market that's
very important
okay okay but you you you can see that
we didn't take any price cutting
I mean there was only one cash card
that's all nothing much
one last question from my side so near
we were listening you know the smaller
players are adding various capacity like
you know 200k CPM such many smaller
players by importing Chinese Machinery
so after this you know MDF margin has
decreased in last couple of water so
possibly such players entry might not be
restricted
I think currently you can see that
despite info despite this nucleus with
uh unorganized approach we are still
able to maintain our business in a good
manner you can see that whatever the
margins affected one reason is it's not
only it's over there I've been industry
it's not only one company
and number two Forex loss is another
part so we we are really not uh I mean
sure I I don't think there will be any
problems of unorganized player and we
really don't see much of the uh capacity
addition in near future and also I would
like to add here that the MDF industry
is growing at the Cher of 20 percent
so there is the the the market is going
to expand and everyone has is going to
get their own share but the difference
here between unorganized clear and
organized queries about the machineries
we bring the German Technologies to make
sure that our efficiency is much more
better than the second and Chinese lines
so my position is 20 25 000 per month or
quarter
per month
I think it's between 20 to 25
000 and we really don't see much of
increase because
I I think this is my personal belief I I
think
this exporter to India's are not making
much business out of this export so
probably further reduction in crisis
question mark and with this model one
cannot bring imported MDF to Northern
Region central region
or to the extent Northeast region
so we see some of the effects and we
have already seen that part despite
cheaper Imports you know we are still
able to maintain our volumes and prices
thank you
okay so someone want to bring the MDS
from south to North so what would be the
additional cost we have to incur in
terms of percentage okay so we are
talking about South to north south to
North and just want to understand the
difference between South and North I'll
use this question pertaining to Imports
or for us
you can reply in both ways important I
tell you if you want to bring it from
Malaysia or Vietnam the ideal part is
Mundra so it's a Mundra to North
okay and then ideally I think it's
costing between 12 to 15 or maybe even
18 percent
okay understood thank you that's it from
myself not a problem thank you
thank you
we are the next station line of Manan
Shah from moneybee Investments please go
ahead
thank you for the opportunity my
question was on this Forex loss of 11.6
crore for the quarter if I look at our
total exports for the quarter uh
laminates as well as MDF I think it
totals to about 58.2 crores and versus
this Forex loss of 11.6 crore when the
currency movement has been fairly stable
between 82 to 80 and this 11.6 amounts
to almost 20 percent of our total export
so I wanted to understand why did we
incur such a big Forex loss and is this
laws attributable entirely to the MDF
segment or it is approving both the two
segments
okay I think it's a good question uh see
uh first of all the total loss which is
11.6 crore is mainly attributed to uh
ndf now when you are saying export uh
when we are just taking the exposure in
terms of Forex it is because of datas
and creditors and I think major part so
far as we are concerned is from uh the
loan which we are already having as of
now so the loan which you have taken uh
for the purpose of AP project
I think that has contributed a major in
terms of that Forex law because the uh
if you compare uh
March versus December
and even in terms of last quarter versus
this quarter I think in both the cases
in USD and Europe both has
depreciated and this has gone against us
and I think you understand and
appreciate also the uh the accounting is
required for the purpose of this
notional entry but yes the two things
are there one is the major part I would
say see otherwise we have
uh natural cage in terms of export
organization versus Forex payment which
is generally the import of robot in
other things
here the Matrix mainly because of the
loan which is outstanding as of now
okay understood uh my second question
was that uh in your opening remarks you
highlighted that there was some increase
in the wood prices uh during the quarter
so if you can just highlight uh what
sort of increase uh was this and uh if
there has been if there has been any
further increase in the wood prices uh
post December
uh the effect of the wood prices is
roughly around eight percent
on an average in uh all the plants this
eight percent is on a why on y basis or
on a Q on Q basis
it's on free on key basis
okay
and uh also we further expect to
increase the wood price by one or two
percent
okay so what has led to such an increase
in the wood prices are not eaten because
I believe there is no other uh
at least within 100 kilometers so
didn't sorry I didn't get your question
can you just repeat it no I'm asking if
what could have been the factors for
such an uh in increase in the wood
prices because I don't believe there's
any other MDF planned in our vicinity
Yeah so basically currently the Andhra
Pradesh is uh recording the highest
number of sales in their eyes and
because of which the transportation cost
has gone up
okay
uh my next question was only uh
utilization levels of the MDF segment so
now it has been almost two years since
we started our new plant and we've only
been uh We've not been able to run paper
ramp it up to almost 80 85 percent so
we've been guiding that we'll reach 85
percent uh by the end of this year
however as it is visible in this quarter
as well we've only been able to achieve
70 so and plus we we have this Conti
booster technology which only we possess
in this country so what have been the
reasons why uh if you can just highlight
a couple of reasons why we are not able
to ramp up our utilizations further
okay in fact uh there are one or two
reasons main reason is uh export we are
consistently uh I think using around
4000 CBM per month that's our Target
and we are putting up a good efforts
like for instance in this quarter we
have added almost 85 new channel
partners
and apart from this capacity
utilizations we are focusing on value
added capacity utilization also so we
are very optimistic of using this
capacity by 80 85 percent incoming days
for sure this is one of our priorities
even in my last call also I have clearly
said that value-added business capacity
utilizations and cost control these are
the three factors and now we have added
one or two more things that we want to
focus on quality and service of product
because now you know import is import
quality is very inferior compared to the
locals there we want to focus on our
quality and services also and we want to
maintain our market share so definitely
in communities I'm sure we'll be able to
part
okay what has been the validated mix of
the vizag plant
I think from nine percent Cube we have
reached to 13 percent
there is one point comparing last year
no right definitely and what are we
targeting by the end of this year
uh it's very difficult to say but you
know our overall Target is to reach 40
percent of entire cells so we are
putting our best reports at present we
are at The Benchmark between 28 to 30
percent
and yeah
okay
um my next question was on the language
segment uh we have shown a remarkable
Improvement in the margins and the
profitability of the segment so if you
can just highlight what led to such a
stack improvement over here
realizations are better uh raw material
price are more or less under control or
reduced rate cost has been you know it's
down like anything and we can say it's
pre-covered level now
okay because if I look at a blended
realizations of on a quarter on quarter
basis a realization per sheet has come
down from 725 to 720 rupees and uh even
in exports are realizations are down but
despite of this lower
there are a lot of other things like you
know when we talk about realization
first heat we are selling 0.5 mm to
shade which may be around seven dollars
too we are selling three mm sheets which
may be thirty forty dollars okay so we
are now taking out this average
so when you have a you know low low
thickness volume then possibly your
realization is down these are the
reasons no what I'm trying to say is
that would trade cost be one of the
major reasons for uh this sort of
improvement in the profitability of the
segments rate is one of the reason I
would say Freight is one of the reason
okay
there are so many other factors like
rice and raw material costs are quite
under the control we have increased our
export volume if you see and also I
would like to add here is the product
mix yes hereby mentioned earlier the
product mix plays a big role in uh
calculation of our average price
right
my last question was on the MDA
statement requested to kindly come back
in the key for follow-up questions done
foreign
Financial please go ahead
yeah uh good morning sir thank you for
the opportunity uh sir can you help us
uh with the the number with respect to
price difference between us and uh some
of the other brands and also on branded
MDF
she uh frankly we don't come across any
unfriended competitions in the market
but yeah it could be around 10 to 12
percent because that segment is
completely different and
and I believe it could be around ten
percent eight to ten percent
yeah ten percent premium to the
unbranded MDS you can say even even if
we compare import if we compare import
landed price in Hyderabad or coimbatore
or Bangalore we are almost 10 to 12
percent higher uh I know it's a bit
technical but let me explain you
whatever the boards we are offering it's
uh it has some specifications it has
some parameters for performance for
instance our density is ranging from 720
to 740 or maybe 750 kg per meter cube
when they are importing in itself in
invoice itself they are mentioning 70 to
690 kg per meter cubes
so these are the things which you know
customer is also considering
right
it's not the same product voting code is
coming even in interior trade even in
plain grid
correct correct now um you know and
compared to the other brands let's say
green panel uh uh you know how different
we would be compared to Green panel
similar board
uh product wise yeah we all guys are
saying more or less technology is more
or less same and
we are working on our product mix
we have our own way of you know
marketing approach they have their ways
so you think we are similar priced
compared to uh even the other side is
always you know some places is plus or
minus I would not agree on that part
okay because it's a it's something
Priceless is something printed
correct
got it answer uh you know when you say
13 of the uh volumes in from vizag plant
is uh value added how do you define the
value add is it this is the uh margin
basis the category of the product what
is it
yeah because if I save my if I if we
talk about our average realizations
then it is maybe around 23 724 rupees
per CBM
and when we talk about uh 13 value added
realization it's almost like 35 000. for
CPM
sorry I'm I'm uh not very clear so
you're saying anything above the Blended
realization is defined as value added is
that so
uh we have a basic product that is the
interior grade okay that's just a plain
MDF board
uh its realization comes around 23 24
000 per CBM but when you add some
performance like you know high density
or water resistance capacity or you put
a paper and pre-lamination on it there
are so many other things right so these
are the category which is around 35 000
and that's that's what around 35 000 is
our organization
got it got it got it and uh just one
clarification on the timber price can
you help us with the timber price on a
rupees per kg basis uh uh for us I'm not
sure but I believe it is around 3 700
rupees per kg per ton
and uh this is for 3Q average
or the current price
I think current price I believe I'm not
sure I need to check
and how about it was like in 2q and 3Q
averager I'm just trying to understand
because
you do around
34 3500 rupees
okay got it uh thank you I'll come back
in the queue sir thank you thank you
very much
thank you
we have the next question from the line
of ritesha from investec please go ahead
hi so thanks for the opportunity for one
very simple question uh how do we
differentiate our products in the
marketplace that's where the first
questions are
well in terms of differentiation number
one we have a three category one
category
we don't much Focus that is unorganized
layer and all these things second is
import against uh you know in that
quality and our quality is different as
I said we focus on two basic para one is
quality another one is Services number
one number two in terms of pre-laminated
mbf law today we have a two range one
range is pre-laminated plus katma which
is a very different texture kind of a
preliminated mbf and then another
section another segment is uh laminate
MDF where we have a hundred plus new
colors every two or three months we keep
adding five ten new backwards according
to the designs and fashion trend in the
market so we focus number three
we definitely demonstrate our products
to all the end user including carpenters
oems and all these people so our Focus
Target is we straight away
approach our end users and channel
Partners in terms of sales and marketing
and we demonstrate our product and we
inform about our quality
sure sir is there any way in which we
actually compensate uh or encourage the
carpenter to use more of our products uh
do we have the technology in place when
we are doing some bundling I think all
the you know organized company probably
they have some kind of a loyalty
programs
okay so what percentage of sales would
that be uh what goes to the carpenter
very tough to say because it's just you
know not in a very large scale like
laminex but in MDF it's now picking up
okay okay
uh is there any numbers over here
no I don't think I can give it right now
I don't have that quicker swiftly
uh sure so my second question was uh
what is the difference between beer MDF
and B uh hdfwr uh basically I understand
the product proposition but if one has
to look at it from a pricing and a
marginal standpoint how different would
that be
okay uh you know we're MDF it's a plain
uh you know basic MDF okay I'm sorry
we're NBA now when we talk about hdfwr
it's a high density fiber board water
resistance board
uh the density of standard MDX body is
around 720 to 740 and this body is
almost 840 to 880 so we are talking
about 20 more density and it's you know
performance like other parameters are
tremendously great
this product is you know you used mainly
in kitchen and wardrobes
and in terms of realization it's almost
one and half and more
and if we talk about margins definitely
it has much better margins
is it possible to quantify something on
the margin profile please
minimum
okay answer how do you say competition
in the marketplace specific to this
particular product like is it unique to
us or are there other players also who
have similar products everyone uh mainly
we don't see much of imports in this
category and uh all organized player are
working hard to promote these products
including us and we are very confident
about the grabbing our market share in
coming
sure this is very helpful and Sir uh the
last question was more on sourcing of
wood uh how do we ensure that the wood
which is being sourced is uh ethical in
nature uh any any policies that we have
in place at the company level how should
we understand this
yeah so we have an uh General criteria
of fixing up the uh how the the how the
moisture level of the wood should be and
basically it's all aggro forestry so we
have certain parameters which has to
work
and this is the most ethical practice of
purchasing the wood
yeah
we are using Agro Forestry
also I would like to add here that we we
are carrying out a program for uh
developing more agroforestry like in
last couple of years we have already
grown more than 12 crore trees and we
have taken admission to grow 4.5 crore
trees this year as well and we'll be
keep on doing this so we make sure that
we do a healthy Agro forestry and you
are which will give us the healthy raw
materials
all right uh sir is there some numbers
over here which is quantifying or
qualifying that whatever would that a
company produces uh it is from macro
forestry uh is is this something which
is audited I'm not very sure I'm still
learning the sector so how should one
understand this particular aspect yeah
the government is not allowing to cut
any kind of a forest so the material
which has to be used are always from the
agroforestry so we educate the Farmers
on this for uh developing their farms in
converting their Farms into viagara
forestry just for an example we take a
boundary wall of the farm where a farmer
is doing some kind of a vegetable which
is ideally not used where we teach them
to make sure that you can grow
agroforestry on your boundary and that
can be later our raw material and which
can also help him to protect his farm
sure well this is quite helpful thank
you so much
thank you
we are the next station of the line of
service Gupta for maximum capital please
go ahead
good morning sir most of my questions
have been answered just on this Forex
loss so can you quantify that what was
the loan in what was the average loan
outstanding in uh foreign currency
during the nine months and what was the
percentage because the percentage
depreciation in rupee would be much
larger so the impact of 11 12 crores is
something that I could not understand
can you quantify him to comments okay uh
see uh if you see other overall date
overall uh date is in the range of 350
crore I am not including the unsecured
loan from the promoters right now out of
that
almost 200 plus crore there are two
loans one is in USD and one is in Europe
the amount is around 200 crores and I
think the difference in terms of Forex
rate I think you know
uh if you compare the with margin again
there's a difference of 78 rupees again
if you compare dollar and Euro both way
I think there is a drastically change
but the overall exposure in terms of
rupees around 200 plus road so far as
the foreign currency loan is concerned
and that is how this loan is coming so
that 11 12 crores actually looks to be
lesser than what it should have been if
you are adjusting for it
in terms of a normal
outstanding uh maybe it is a export
maybe I think import but the net impact
after adjusting the uh the natural hedge
benefit
so the net impact is this so and this is
not I think one particular
currency it is both weight one way it is
uh Euro and another way it is USD so the
combination of both of them will come to
this particular figure in the previous
quarter and even NASA also we have a
positive I think impact but for the last
one quarter specifically we have this
losses so when we are taken this loan we
had not hedged our exposure to this loan
uh by buying forward contracts no LLC
when we have got this loan uh so far as
the Euro loan is concerned it was like
at the rate of 0.85 only
but because of the last I think three
four months RBI uh initiatives in terms
of increase in rate that has affected
and we uh our cost which was Point 85
has reached to more than three percent
now
and similarly in terms of
USD also USD also was again linked with
Libor but then so far I think for the
last Almost one year we had not seen any
major fluctuation and that is how we had
covered but it was not covered fully
because of this metal age Factor but
recently because of this thing graphic
change it has affected but now
internally we have taken it very
seriously and we are just taking some
action in such a way that at least we
should not have a situation feature
okay because otherwise every quarter
depending on how the exchange rate
movement is you will have a Forex loss
or income going forward yes yes it is
like um as for the India's guideline and
I think we are just following that
guideline only
so as per the suggestion of auditor and
see as a policy if you compare this
other company
they each company has a different policy
to disclose in financial differently
so as of now we are just so far as
profit is concerned we are showing in
other income and if it is a loss then we
are showing in uh other manufacturing
expense
so unlike other companies we are not uh
showing it in finance cost and secondly
as of now we don't have any project
which is running or you know
implementation stage so there is a thing
to be capitalized so for today's concern
understood enter in terms of the now
that we are almost through with this
financial year so what will be the kind
of Revenue guidance and ebitda margins
for for the coming year in laminate and
MDF
we I think I just want to be able to
give you these figures but I can
definitely tell you that Uh current
quarter has impact of price and other
things and because of this Forex loss
but I think so far as I understand I
think this this current quarter that is
January to March I think that
won't be so much Forex situation that is
what I believe but I may be wrong also
so far as the overall margin is
concerned I think as QB has said we are
already working on couple of things
where on one side the valuable products
we are just increasing secondly we are
putting our efforts in terms of
increasing capacity and third is like
the overall optimization of costs so we
would definitely maintain our margins
which is where if you can see our
overall margin in the nine month figure
I think we'll definitely maintain that
margin
I meant for the FI 24 next year what
kind of growth and margins we are
looking at the growth wise I think uh 15
20 growth in terms of
revenue is definitely there and margin
wise we will improve that is for sure
understood so in the right ratio what
kind of problems
follow-up questions
participant
participants the request will kindly
restrict your questions to two per
participant
we have the next question of the line of
Krishna s from vihar's advisors please
go ahead yeah thank you very much for
the opportunity and uh uh I I guess uh
the management is really working hard uh
you know considering the external Factor
because we are living in a world where
we are very much co-dependent on the
external factors Global factors and on
so having said that uh so and plus most
of my questions have already been put up
but uh one or two questions remain so
one among that is that uh like if we
consider the current quarter gone by
which is the third quarter of the
current Financial year adding back the
Forex losses so can that be considered
as you know uh a reasonable figure going
forward for the next two three quarters
for profitability
see I think uh this quarter is the
abnormal quarter so far as the forest
loss is concerned not for me for
everybody I think across the industry
and I think you can also understand and
appreciate that part uh so far as our
part is concerned I think as I said in
the earliest version uh we don't see
much more fluctuation just like last
person may not be there in the current
quarter that is generally marked and I
think Way Forward I think I'm not able
to give you any any comment on that part
so far as Forex party solution so far as
the profitable concerned I think we are
looking forward in terms of very
positive so far as we Improvement in
terms of margins it is definitely there
in the next next one year
so we can see that we can so in short to
put it very simply so once we add back
the foreign
thanks for that and the second question
is so that with respect to rights issue
so rights issue finally we have come up
with a figure of around 125 CR uh
roughly here under crore here and there
so now this 200 we have taken an
approval so any uh chance of you know
going for a further like you know
further or we'll restrict to that figure
that we have filed at er actually
okay now see as of now as for the uh
filing which is done and as for the
first file in the draft filing we
already put that figure and as for the
CD guideline and the lodr we can
increase this amount by 20 percent or we
can decrease this amount by 20 percent
so uh from 124 crore 2 we can go up to
149 on upper side and we can just fix
our right issue at around 99
within next couple of days we will just
decide internally and we'll finalize the
a couple of things in terms of right
issues one is the I think Rising part
and second is the standing also
because see we are looking forward in
terms of this right issue and as we
mentioned in the object we would like to
reduce this promoters
loan by adjusting into Equity that is
first part and that amount is around 57
crore remaining part is like working
capital where we are looking at at these
a couple of opportunities related to
cooperation level not the expansion part
see uh when we started this project in
AP in last year we had exposure of
working capital it was around 84 crore
in terms of CC that is fund based
facilities now even after this achieving
capacity of 70 plus
percentage and still we have not
increased this working capital
facilities and we are managing the same
thing within this limit only so uh
considering uh I think today's position
where they are looking at uh Way Forward
in terms of other penetration in terms
of areas in India also so I think we may
need some working capital so that is how
we have planned in such a way that in
case of the requirements we can
definitely get that working capital
immediately and that is how we have
planned for this right issue so if you
see this uh this happens as for the our
internal timeline
so it should complete if there is no
change in terms of management decision
then I think it will be able to complete
this right issue in March if that is the
case then I think uh in terms of that 57
crore will be reduced so far as promoter
part is concerned and secondly as for
the normal repayment scheduled we are
already repaying that would be around 45
crore so practically in large balance
sheet compared to uh March 22 March 23
will have at least 100 crore Less in
terms of date
and secondly uh if you compare with
profitability in last March versus March
23 I think will be in a better position
and that is already evident in the last
two three quarters so our dtp ratio will
decrease like anything so that is what
we are planning and secondly when I uh
right issue is already completed in
March I think we'll be sitting on cash
uh comfortably so far
great great it seems to be a good like a
good calculation so I think great so I
think uh we should uh you know uh the
way that we are strategizing we should
look at it and then uh I think it will
be good and uh now to the last question
so uh we have uh so so the foreign
currency load so though it looked in the
initial stage it looked a little cheap
but uh this is the experience of many
companies at later stages because of the
exchange rate fluctuation that uh
foreign currency loan starts to look a
little bit you know that benefit is
diminished with respect to the rupee
loan so what has been the experience of
the company so in the future like you
know because as it has the company come
to the conclusion that Forex loan Visa
is the rupee loan the advantage is not
much and what would we ever take for the
future expansion
okay see
so far today is concerned
just a minute
the uh in terms of uh when we had
planned for the loan it was very very I
think uh lucrative I'll just give you
example of Euro loan that is 0.85
percent and you know the considering the
Hedge I think the missile head which we
have so far it was very very uh
competitive and in terms of our finance
costs uh till last quarter I think our
final score in terms of overall it was
in the range of five to six percent now
last quarter I think this has changed
and that has changed by at least two to
three percent now coming to your
question fee uh we are already looking
at the option of converting this loan
into rupee loan also uh however I think
we will have to have a couple of options
and then we will decide on this part but
so far I think our experience is very
good so
but then I think after having this
quarter will definitely internally look
at it and we'll plan to either hedge at
some accent or we can can also plan for
converting some part of the loan into uh
rupee loan also that is also I think
possible
yeah understood understood fair enough
so that's all from my side thank you
very much sir and uh good luck uh for
the days ahead
thank you
we are the next mission line of Anand
Sony from Pro iniquity please go ahead
thank you
we have the next question of the line of
Hina from damn Capital please go ahead
yeah hi thank you for the opportunity uh
I just wanted some understanding on
laminate uh on the domestic sideways
that uh organized competition is coming
back so one has that been happening and
the second would be on raw materials
this type of cooling off are we passing
that on to the channel or are we
retaining some part of it
unorganized players are coming back in a
big way into the market is that would
that be true is that impacting demand
no no it's since long I mean they are
not the first one coming now it's it has
been years so it's something not the
second thing we are almost if we talk
about our exports uh mix
yeah nine months is almost 65 percent is
our exports and 35 percent is domestic
Market okay and we are focusing our
product in a different segment where you
know uh interior and specifiers are
working
sure
that's one of the reason as long as raw
material price is concerned I think it's
quite stable
yeah it may go down it may not increase
further yeah yeah yeah so I think
chemical prices have already got that
right
uh
see it's K2 case I mean not necessary
company like company like us we are
working more on a you know a specifier
in all these places
oh
[Music]
everybody don't say any person
okay and on the export side uh we hear
that you're slowing down some to demand
so would that be impacting us you know
say near to medium term
no we don't export a lot in America and
Europe
we more or less exports in Asia
southeast Asia and Gulf countries okay
now we see in fact very good demand oh
thank you so much thank you thank you
very much
thank you we have the next question the
line of Arun bed from ICICI Securities
please go ahead
hi sir uh you know can you help us is
the ex when you mentioned that the
margin is mdfully maintained was that
with the context of Q3 margins or nine
months margins
okay I think I had already mentioned
very category when we are talking about
future I am just talking about the uh
nine months marching
yes exactly yeah and so on the export
realization
have they come down further from the
follow liberal numbers of roughly 19 000
in Q3
yeah I think it's more or less stable
now
at 18 and a half the same number as Q3
because now you know we don't see much
of a change in Freight also in uh
selling price are more or less safe
okay and so just one more data point is
uh how the margin is different as
compared to exports and domestic
see uh but there are things different
than definitely but I just can't comment
exactly in terms of uh
percentage or a value but uh
if you compare a last couple of quarters
I think we have improved in terms of
volume so far as the export is concerned
and we are just trying to maintain the
margin as of now waveform compared to
last I mean Financial year and covered
impact yes there was a impact but then
now it has been stabilized so this
margins will continue that is what I can
tell you so I appreciate your point just
a ball path like if theoretically let's
assume that you know the wasting is X
then export would be what 0.7 x 1.3 X
how should you look at it yeah uh if you
just see our realization uh in terms of
dominance civilization is around in the
range of 24 000 right now coming to
export it is in the range of eighteen
thousand so I think it is very evident
in terms of realization part so far as
the costing part is concerned this there
may be a difference in terms of cost
component considering the specific cost
it is attached to this export but
relation wise it is 24 000 overall
versus uh 18 000 odd but I would like to
add there are some hidden benefits to uh
number one in exports normally we have
only one or two or three thickness and
we run this production for a day or two
or something like that so we Save A Lot
on these parts second using applications
of marginal cost third thing
utilizations of capacity fourth thing
maintaining our market share in export
because we have decided that we will
definitely promote three to four
thousand CBM per month in
region uh where you know MDF is we can
export and uh because we are talking
about natural age also these are the you
know some of the benefits and last thing
which we don't forget is we have
obligations also so we have to export
certain quantities
and the last questions uh we are you
know more or less utilizing our capacity
by 50 percent uh you know on a full
capacity uh this number next year for
the full year we should look at what
percentage as competitive transition
I think what we are talking about is 80
to 85 percent that's our Target minimum
so we are working hard on this part
definitely 85 but we are also trying to
go more if we get an opportunity in
export Market or anywhere so we are
ready for 1900 whatever but that's our
goal and as long as our value addition
is concerned I think in my previous call
also I have mentioned that we want to
reach 240 to 50 percent so we are doing
almost 62 to 65 percent from chicken
plant
enter assuming we can do 80 85 which is
your target uh the mix would be similar
between domestic exports or uh would it
be much different no I believe we have a
target of 4000 CB employers that's what
our Target is so we want to go around 48
to 50 000 CBM per year
okay okay thank you very much for this
thank you very much
thank you
we have the next question from the line
of Rajesh Kumar Ravi from HDFC
Securities please go ahead
yeah hi sir good afternoon
late so you know I have missed some of
your remarks uh first is on the uh ndf
uh if I look at export versus do
mistakes uh why is there such a sharp
difference or you know for the Imports
Landing in India uh you know and even
export margins that we Indian companies
make compared to the chip margins we
understand that there is a sharp
difference uh export margins are very
low so where do we uh you know uh is it
the cost of Indian manufacturer
production cost for them in
manufacturers are much higher compared
to those coming from Southeast Asia
uh I think uh if I'm not mistaken uh
there are uh I think players like from
Thailand and Vietnam they are exporting
in Gulf region and more or less our
price and their prices are same
and second part there is a change in
realization could be fob and CI to CIF
part also
otherwise uh you know whatever the rate
difference Thailand or Vietnam is
getting that's their benefit or loss and
whatever the credit benefits we are
getting that's our loss of coffee
otherwise Market is there and I think
it's almost like for example two hundred
dollars so probably it's more or less
same for Indian players or high player
or Vietnam
it's always on a safe basis or maybe you
know if everybody is there is afraid so
this could be the reason
so what I am trying to understand the
southern ports the Imports which are
coming in uh they are at 10 to 20 or
almost 20 percent cheaper compared to
the cost of Indian producers uh selling
price of Indian producers why should
there be such a large difference I am
assuming the the exporters to India
would not be selling at very thin margin
or a loss is that understanding correct
uh if we talk about uh you know
their realizations it's more or less
same if we consider whatever the price
they get for the Dubai for instance or
general report or Fortune airport more
or less their realization is only four
or five dollar plus or minus that's all
now another thing is very important is
they do not have you know demand for
Europe Market or American market so for
them selling this capacity is very
important they cannot sell some quantity
or 100 quantity to one country otherwise
you know that price will fall so they
always balance sometimes they sell it to
Gulf some part decided to India
so is it akin to what the situation we
would be looking at for at least next to
one two years when we India is adding a
good chunk of new capacities
yeah yeah no no what I am looking at for
next one year and two years India uh in
this capacity which are coming up
because we would also be looking at
domestic obviously there is no
contesting that India is looking at
strong growth opportunities and hence
all these capacities eventually will get
absorbed and more would be required but
in the mainstream setting up is not
going to be at 100 from day one okay no
no where I am coming in from like India
is also exporting at low margins as an
opportunistic sales is it the similar
situation that the Imports Landing in
India at low cost is more of an
opportunistic sale and not the recurring
sale which is meant for Europe and all
so once demand improves in Europe U.S
market the supply pressure firm exports
Landing in India let me reduce
definitely there will be increase in the
price so definitely and that will also
help us Indian prayer because indirectly
even in other Market country like Golf
and all these places there will be price
increase so you know indirectly it will
be benefit for us also when it comes to
exports not only competition and
second part is maintaining volume is
very important for every company in
Indian market and at present if you see
from Q2 despite import if we talk about
our sales volume
in Q2 it was uh I would say we did it
around 54 000 CBN now in Q3 we did it
around 57 000 CBN
and how did export number uh how much of
this is exported sorry if I missed that
comes around 13 000 something and last
quarter it was around 10 000. okay so
you have seen good jump in your export
volumes
to maintain 4000 CBM per month per month
okay so you're close to your 100 now
you're already achieved 100 and this
will be maintained
correct so incrementally your growth
will be driven from a domestic Market
penetration only
yes domestic Market was good too foreign
four thousand CBN
sorry 44 45 000 CBM now this term it is
45 so we can see around two three
percent growth in domestic Market too
and importantly from value addition
point of view from our AP plant we have
grown from nine percent to 13 that's
very important
okay and you said that around 26 margin
could be sustainable numbers here on
25 26 range you don't see any measures
to that margin numbers for you
okay and laminates this quarter margins
ten percent seems to be uh better off
compared to the preceding many quarters
so do you see this as now a structural
Improvement
yeah we believe we believe it will have
a good Improvement in coming days is it
because more valuated products would you
got ex you were able to sell higher in
exports Market very valuation
requirement is more uh yeah you are
right it's all about product mix number
one it's all about uh price stick
decrease in Freight also number three we
have a quite stable row material
pricings even some places is going down
to
and demand is really good so I think
that there are so many effectors
okay last question in the uh can you
give the PVC uh a bitter number
uh see I
EDC if you consider the overall volume
in terms of value and value volume it is
hardly one percent of total uh I think
sales so it is very my number say it is
in material so far as the figures are
concerned okay you know why I'm asking
this because I would answer this
question if we talk about nine months
from minus 13 to minus six percent so we
have a substantial Improvement in seven
to eight percent
and if we compare from our last quarter
from minus 16 percent to minus six
percent so we have improved almost 10
percent in terms of Evita margin okay
okay
and MDF how much is a foreign
now we have reached to minus two percent
so we are very close to the Target and
last Financial year is I mean uh I'm
sure minus 13 to minus two so we are
doing quite good right right at least at
least continue let's talk about uh uh
nine years come nine months comparison
from minus 16 percent ebitda we have
reached to one percent beta so we are in
now positive part positive at least and
so Forex loss how much is there in the
MDF and all because what you've reported
is uh Neto for uh text of Forex loss
which is there in terms of uh Euro and
USD
but that have to be booked through a
bitter only uh that should go through
into the interest part right not in the
beta portion no it is not that way see
there are a couple of uh ways to uh
manage this thing we have followed the
accounting policy where we uh there is a
profit we are just
showing it in the other income and so
far as if it is a loss then we are
showing it to other manufacturing costs
now your question see when it comes to
finance costs generally it is like uh
Whenever there is a uh accounting policy
which is decided that any differential
part in terms of foreign currency laws
loan versus same loan if it is taken in
uh domestic currency then the
differential part we can park in this
Finance course but it is again for
accounting policy which each company has
to follow and this has to be I think
consistently followed so we are
following and as I said profit in other
income laws in other manufacturing cost
okay okay for nine months how much is
the part of the cost which is
before starting the actual production of
an expansion or a capex then definitely
we can capitalize that capitalize
website
we don't have anything which is being
capitalized yes yes and so for nine
months the products loss would be how
much which is gone in other expenses it
is 12 point or 11.62 crore only
everything is in this quarter when the
yes it is well covered so far as nine
months is concerned for quarter it is
11.62
right right so most of the losses is
incurred in this quarter which is dented
the reported ebitda margin significantly
okay uh I think that's all from my
answer thank you all the best
okay thank you
thank you
that was the last question you would now
like to hand it over to the management
for closing comments
uh thank you once again for your
interest and support we'll we'll
continue to stay engaged
please be in touch with our PR agency
and factors or investor relation team
for any other further details or
discussion look forward to interacting
with you next quarter thank you
is limited that concludes this
conference thank you for joining us any
minute disconnect your lines
thank you